What you're watching here is, I'm noticing already, what you're watching here is students gathered in Tennessee demanding that these greedy lawmakers care more about their lives than what they're making from the NRA.
Rise like the water.
They've been used in all the school shootings.
Let me ask y'all this.
Why don't we ban assault rifles?
You don't need those.
Those are just for Army.
These are war weapons.
Everyday people should not own assault weapons at all.
What are you doing with your military war weapons?
Hold on, let him answer that.
I'd like to ask, what do you feel like that would do to make us safer in society?
Because assault rifles are only used by-
Hang on, I'd like to hear this show, man, if y'all don't mind.
Hold up, guys.
Would y'all like to hear him or not?
No, they want to hear from you.
They want to hear from you.
Justin, we've heard enough out of you, young man.
Yeah.
The person Representative Lamberth is speaking down to, who is off camera, is Tennessee State Representative Justin Jones, otherwise known as Brother Jones.
I just want to say happy Black History Month before we make that illegal.
Who has tirelessly spoken on behalf of Black folks since he has been elected to office and is now speaking on behalf of these kids.
And don't get it twisted, young man ain't no different than boy.
Enough is enough!
It's not an issue of left or right, it's a moral issue of right and wrong.
The majority of the citizens support common sense gun legislation.
Thursday, when thousands of students and mothers and parents and grandparents showed up to the Capitol peacefully.
Peacefully.
Yes!
To call for an end to the terror.
For an end to school children being massacred.
And rather than respond to the Tennesseans from across the state who gathered at the State House.
A small group of extremists mischaracterized those people as insurrectionists.
Children who were in the hallway saying, please, I want to live.
Preschoolers with their parents.
And so that's why we said we could not go about business as normal on the house floor.
Because when you see something that is wrong, you have a moral obligation to get in the way.
Moment of silence.
To pray for the children.
We need to do something about gun control.
Representative Pearson, stay on the bill.
I don't want to have to start ruling out order again.
Please on voting.
If a member is deemed absent by the clerk during voting, the clerk shall lock the member's electronic roll call machine.
Mr. Speaker, members of the other side of the aisle always wear pins that say the NRA.
They wear pins with the AR-15 on it.
But you're telling me that I cannot wear a pin with a picture of an AR-15?
Representative Jones.
So please don't say you're pro-life and then vote to put more weapons on the street.
Representative Mitchell, you are.
Hey, no, I will speak.
You know, sir, you're under welcoming and honoring.
Representative Mitchell, you're out.
No action.
No peace.
Inaction is radical.
What is going on here needed something that was serious, a serious response to the inaction of this body.
Both Justin and Representative Gloria Johnson have been removed from their standing committees and subcommittees because of their efforts in speaking on behalf of the constituencies and other constituencies that elected them.
No peace.
Point of order.
You may have served from the diocese.
Why not?
Let her speak.
Again.
The standing house rules do not allow for mile away.
You're not recognized.
I recognize her.
I recognize her, yeah.
That's our representative.
I recognize her.
You have been warned.
I don't see my colleague who represents this area here, but I stand with you.
Yeah.
As a representative.
Call on those who live in this community.
Governor Bill Lee.
Officer Blackburn.
Don't say boo, but I'll say come out here and stand with your own people.
Yeah.
The time for an action has passed.
It's time to do something.
Yeah.
And so when those children walk out of school on Monday, I'll be with them and I hope you'll turn up as well.
Thank you to all of the children and everyone who is assisting them in stepping up and doing what needs to be done in Tennessee and what needs to ripple through this country.
And thank you to Tennessee Holla for keeping us informed beyond the state lines of Tennessee on the ways in which this country is continuing to oppress and the ways in which we need to be raising our voices to challenge it.
On the house floor, all they had were moments of silence.
No.
The time for silence is over.
Yeah.